今天课的主题是系统调试。
The topic of today's class is systematic debugging.
有时你别无选择，只能调试。
Sometimes you have no choice but to debug.
我们讨论了避免在早期的类中进行调试。
We talked about avoiding debugging in an earlier class.
但是当你有一个虫子，而且它只被发现
But when you have a bug and it's found only
当你把整个系统连接起来，
when you plug the whole system together,
或者当你使用一个报告[听不见]系统
or when you use a reports [INAUDIBLE] the system is
部署，然后你必须找到它在哪里。
deployed, then you have to find where it is.
对于这些情况，我们有一个系统的策略
For those situations, we have a systematic strategy
这可以使调试更加有效。
that can make debugging more effective.
第一步是复制它。
First step is reproducing it.
这意味着确保你能看到同样的错误
That means making sure that you can actually see the same bug
您的用户已报告的。
that your user has reported.
事实上，最好你能复制它
And in fact, it's best if you can reproduce it
一个小的可重复的测试用例。
with a small and repeatable test case.
如果你通过回归测试发现了这个错误，
Now if you found the bug by regression testing,
那么你已经有了那个测试用例。
then you already have that test case.
这是测试套件中失败的测试用例。
That's the failing test case in your test suite.
如果用户报告[听不见]，
If it was [INAUDIBLE] reported by a user,
可能需要一些努力，首先要得到相同的行为--
it may take some effort, first to get the same behavior--
用户看到的同样的不良行为。
the same bad behavior that the user is seeing.
事实上，在某些情况下，
Then in fact, with some situations,
像图形用户界面或多线程程序，
like graphical user interfaces or multi-threaded programs,
可能很难持续复制，
it may actually be hard to reproduce it consistently,
如果这取决于事件发生的时间--
if it depends on timing of events--
当你点击按钮的时候--
precisely when you click the button--
或者这取决于线程的交织方式。
or if it depends on how threads interleave.
但你能做的任何努力
But any effort you can make in making that test
小而可重复的情况——也就是说，每次你
case small and repeatable-- that is, always fail every time you
运行它——会有回报的，因为你可能
run it-- will pay off, because you'll probably
在你搜索的时候必须一遍又一遍地运行这个测试用例
have to run that test case over and over while you search
去解决这个错误。
for the bug and try to fix it.
一旦你成功修复了这个错误，
And once you successfully fix the bug,
然后这个小的，可重复的测试用例
then this small, repeatable test case
会做一个很好的回归测试
will make a great regression test
你只需要做个测试
that you'll just put in your test
如果虫子再出现就会找到它的套房。
suite that will find that bug if it ever crops up again.
所以一旦你有了这个bug的测试用例，
So once you have a test case for the bug,
那么你的目标就是做这个测试
then your goal is simply to make that test
工作——让它变成绿色，这非常令人满意。
work-- to make it turn green, and that's very satisfying.
这里有一个例子。
So here's an example.
假设你有这个功能。
So suppose you have this function.
它应该在字符串中找到最常用的单词。
It's supposed to find the most common word in a string.
所以它接受一个字符串作为输入。
So it takes a string as an input.
以及字符串的前提条件
And the precondition on that string
它包含零个或多个单词，
is that it contains zero or more words,
其中一个单词是由字母数字字符组成的字符串
where a word is a string of alphanumeric characters
以非字母数字字符为界。
that's bounded by non-alphanumeric characters.
这个函数应该返回，
And this function is supposed to return,
作为后置条件，一个出现频率最高的词
as its postcondition, a word that occurs maximally often
在文本中，忽略字母大小写。
in the text, ignoring alphabetic case.
换句话说，我们将处理大小写
In other words, we're going to treat uppercase and lowercase
当我们比较单词时也是一样。
as the same when we're comparing words.
所以现在假设一个用户把莎士比亚的
So now suppose a user takes the entire text of Shakespeare's
播放并将其连接为字符串
plays and concatenates that into a string
通过你的方法发现
and passes it in your method and discovers
而不是返回一个可预见的
that instead of returning a predictably
常用英语单词--“the”和“a”
common English word-- "the" and "a"
是英语中最常见的词，
are some of the most common words in the English language,
所以我们希望它们经常发生
so we would expect them to occur very frequently
在莎士比亚的作品中，我们得到了一些
in Shakespeare-- we instead get something that isn't even
一个词，比如“e”
a word, like "e."
现在这是一个巨大的投入。
Now this is an enormous input.
大约10万行文字，总共80万字。
It's about 100,000 lines of text, 800,000 words total.
这个输入将很难去bug
This input is going to be very difficult to de-bug
用正常的方法。
by normal methods.
如果我们把打印的声明放在体内
If we put print statements inside the body
在这个函数中，我们有几十万个
of this function, we'd have hundreds of thousands
当它在细嚼细嚼的时候。
of print statements as it was chewing through that string.
或者我们在这里设置断点，
Or if we put breakpoints in here,
我们会在上百个断点
we would be hitting those breakpoints hundreds
无数次。
of thousands of times.
因此，如果我们改为
So debugging would be much easier if we instead
将此输入的大小减小为可管理的
reduce the size of this input to something manageable that
仍然显示相同或非常相似的错误。
still exhibits the same, or a very similar, bug.
这里有一些你可以用来减少的策略。
Here's some strategies you can use for that reduction.
你可以把输入分成两半。
You can cut the input in half.
莎士比亚的前半部分也有同样的缺陷吗？
Does the first half of Shakespeare show the same bug?
这是二进制搜索的一种形式
It's a form of binary search, which
一直是计算机科学中的一项好技术。
is always a good technique in computer science.
我们要多谈谈
And we're going to talk more about it
稍后阅读。
later on in this reading.
如果你只用一个剧本怎么办？
What if you use just a single play?
有几十场戏。
There is a couple dozen plays.
如果你只选一个剧本
What if you pick just a single play
看看它是否也有同样的缺陷？
and see whether it exhibits the same bug?
如果你只选一个演讲怎么办--
What if you pick just a single speech--
只是一出戏的几句台词。
just a few lines from a play.
那有相同的错误吗？
Does that have the same bug?
所以我们可以减少输入直到得到一个小测试用例。
So we can reduce the input until we get a small test case.
然后我们会有更多的运气使用技巧
And then we'll have more luck using techniques
比如打印调试和断点调试。
like print debugging and breakpoint debugging.
然后我们用那个小测试用例修复这个bug。
Then we fix the bug using that small test case.
但我们还是想回到原来的马车上
But then we still want to go back to the original buggy
输入100000-100000行，800000字--
input-- to the 100,000-- 100,000 lines, 800,000 words--
并确认它确实修复了该输入
and confirm that it actually fixes it for that input
也。
as well.